Inventory of the Latvijas PSR Valsts Drošības Komiteja [Latvian KGB] selected records
Hoover Institution Archives
Latvijas PSR Valsts Drošības Komiteja [Latvian KGB] selected records
1944-2012
2017C8
Hoover Institution Archives
1286 digital files (717.77 GB)
Latvijas PSR Valsts Drošības Komiteja.
Abstract
Reports and other documents relating to secret police activities in Latvia. Digital copies.
Location of Original Materials
Originals in: Latvijas Valsts Vēstures Arhīvs, Riga, Latvia.
Access
The collection is open for research. Users must sign use agreement.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Latvian branch of the Soviet secret police organization Komitet gosudarstvennoǐ bezopasnosti.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports and other documents relating to secret police activities in Latvia. Digital copies.
Secret service--Soviet Union.; Police--Soviet Union.; Police--Latvia; Latvia--History--1940-1991.
- Fond 1846, grave books of German prisoners-of-war buried in Latvia, 1945-1950; 31 digital files (Reading room workstation)
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior LSSR prisoner-of-war camps, special hospitals (51 pages), 1948 January 12 - 1949 December 3
  - Grave books of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior LSSR prisoner-of-war camp, special hospitals in 1948-1949 (9 pages), 1948 January 1 - 1949 January 1
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 277 in Riga (49 pages), 1945 March 16 - December 30
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 277 graves in Riga, Klijanu Street (Lielie kapi); Riga city Agricultural Department's permit for the use of land site; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in March-December, 1945 (29 pages), 1945-1949
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 277 graves in Riga, Gaujas Street 12 (Meža kapi); permit for the use of land site, deed of conveyance of graves; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in January-August, 1946 (13 pages), 1946-1950
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 317 in Riga (51 pages), 1945 May 25 - 1947 October 17
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 317 graves in Riga, Meza prospekts 88 (Sarkandaugava); permit for the use of land site; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1945-1947 (13 pages), 1945-1949
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 3338 in Riga (52 pages), 1945 July 24 - 1947 March 11
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior Special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 3338 graves in Riga, Livciema Street 88 (Ziepniekkalns); deed of conveyance of graves; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1945-1947 (11 pages), 1945-1949
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior Special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 3338 graves in Riga, Livciema Street 2 (Group 73); decision of Riga City Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People; permit for the use of land site; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1947-1949 (12 pages)
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior Special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 4379 graves in Riga, Livciema Street (Group 73a); grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1945-1946 (17 pages), 1945-1949
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior Special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 4379 graves in Riga, Livciema Street (Group 73a); grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1946-1947 (14 pages)
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 4379 in Riga (28 pages), 1945 July 8 - 1946 June 26
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior special prisoner-of-war hospital No. 4379 in Riga (30 pages), 1946 June 25 - 1947 December 26
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 292, Section No. 5 graves in Daugavpils; excerpt from Daugavpils Executive Committee's protocol about land allotment; deed of conveyance of graves; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1946-1948 (13 pages), 1946-1949
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 292, Department No. 5 in Daugavpils (31 pages), 1946 April 1 - 1948 October 13
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 266 graves in Jelgava; Jelgava City Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People decision about land allotment; deed of conveyance of graves; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1945-1946 (12 pages), 1945-1949
  - Layout and schemes of USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 266, Section No.1 graves in Jelgava; grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in 1946-1949 (8 pages)
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Prisoner-of-war camp No. 266, Section No. 1 in Jelgava (27 pages), 1946 February 9 - 1949 September 30
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Krustpils' prisoner-of-war camp No. 292 in 1945-1946; Krustpils parish Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People permission of land allotment; deed of conveyance of graves; layout and schemes of Camp No. 292 and Camp No. 292, Section 6 graves (11 pages), 1945-1949
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 266 in Krustpils (49 pages), 1945 July 30 - December 20
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Kuldiga's prisoner-of-war camp No. 349, Section No. 4 in 1947-1948; Kuldiga district Executive Committee's permission to bury prisoners-of-war; deed of conveyance of graves, layout of graves; alphabetical book of dead prisoners-of-war (46 pages), 1947-1949
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Liepaja prisoner-of-war camp No. 349, Section No. 20 in 1945-1946; layout and schemes of graves; Liepaja City Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People permission to bury prisoners-of-war; alphabetical book of dead prisoners-of-war (42 pages), 1945-1949
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Liepaja prisoner-of-war camp No. 349, Section No. 20 in 1946-1947; layout and schemes of graves; Liepaja City Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People permission to bury prisoners-of-war; alphabetical book of dead prisoners-of-war (57 pages), 1946-1949
  - Grave book and lists of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Ogre prisoner-of-war camps No. 391 and No. 291, Section No. 40 and special facility No. 40; deed of land allotment; deed of conveyance of graves; layout-scheme of graves (14 pages), 1945-1950
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Olaine's prisoner-of-war camp No. 277, Section No. 10 in 1945; layout and schemes of graves; Olaine parish Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People notice of land allotment; layout-scheme of graves; alphabetical book of dead prisoners-of-war (41 pages), 1945-1949
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Rezekne's prisoner-of-war camp No. 292, Section No. 5 in 1945-1946; Makasanu parish Kleperu village council's notice of land allotment; deed of conveyance of graves; layout and schemes of graves; alphabetical book of dead prisoners-of-war (39 pages)
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 277, Section No. 1 in Salaspils (51 pages), 1945 April 5 - 1946 May 15
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Salaspils prisoner-of-war camp No. 277, Section No. 1 in 1945-1946; Salaspils parish Executive Committee permission to use for German prisoners-of-war graves; deed of conveyance of graves; layout-schemes of graves (19 pages), 1945-1949
  - Alphabetical book of German Army prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior prisoner-of-war camp No. 350, Section No. 6 in Ventspils (49 pages), 1945 July 7 - 1948 August 9
  - Grave book of prisoners-of-war who died in USSR Ministry of Interior Ventspils prisoner-of-war camp No. 350, Section No. 6 in 1945-1948; Ventspils City Executive Committee of the Deputy Council of Working People decision to accept land; deed of conveyance of graves and scheme (12 pages), 1945-1949
- Fond 1847, USSR People's Commissariat for Internal Affairs (Ministry of State Security) Internal Troop's 5th Rifle division, 1944-1956; 16 digital files (Reading room workstation)
  - Battle operation record book of Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 24th Rifle regiment (51 pages), 1946-1949
  - Alphabetical book of 24th Rifle regiment officers who participated in combat against national underground activities in territory of Latvia (305 pages), 1946-1951
  - 24th Rifle regiment's battle commands, short descriptions of battle operations, and information about soldier participation in combat against national partisans (54 pages), 1946-1951
  - Personnel record book of 24th Rifle regiment's subordinate units (221 pages), 1946-1951
  - Alphabetical book of Lithuanian SSR Ministry of State Security servicemen who participated in combat against Lithuanian national underground activities (290 pages), 1945-1949
  - Record book of USSR Ministry of State Security 5th Rifle division officers who participated in combat against national underground activities in Baltic republics (235 pages), 1945-1952
  - Battle operation record book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 143rd Rifle regiment's subordinate units (101 pages), 1944-1945
  - Battle operation record book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's subordinate units (107 pages), 1944-1950
  - Alphabetical record book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's warrior war missions (191 pages), 1945-1953
  - Alphabetical book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's warriors who participated in battle operations (340 pages), 1951-1956
  - Battle operation record book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's subordinate units (281 pages), 1945-1953
  - Battle operation record book of USSR Ministry of State Security Internal Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's subordinate units (125 pages), 1944-1945
  - War missions register of USSR Ministry of State Security 5th Rifle division's subordinate units' soldiers (120 pages), 1947-1955
  - Record book of battle operations against national underground activities carried out by LSSR districts' militia departments (111 pages), 1945-1950
  - Extract from International Troop's 36th Rifle regiment's historical form (7 pages), 1945-1950
  - Extract from International Troop's 24th Rifle regiment's historical form (50 pages), 1945-1950
- Fond 1994, personal files of German-nationality citizens, stateless people, religious sect participants, and antisocial elements who were deported from Latvia from 1941 to 1953, 1944-2012; 1239 digital files (Reading room workstation)
  PDF Inventory
  PDF Inventory of Fond 1994